<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Page</title>
    <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:55:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sheel2007.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Web Application with Python</title>
      <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/building-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sheel2007.github.io/building-web-app/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Before we get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have Python installed on your computer. You can download Python from the official website. We&amp;rsquo;ll also be using Flask, which is a Python web framework. You can install it using pip, the Python package manager, by running the following command:&#xA;pip install flask Creating a Basic Flask Application Once you have Flask installed, let&amp;rsquo;s create a basic Flask application. Create a new Python file and import the Flask class:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Debugging Your Code Like a Pro</title>
      <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 12:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sheel2007.github.io/tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Reproduce the Issue Before you start debugging, you need to be able to reproduce the issue. Make sure you can reliably trigger the bug or error. This will help you understand the scope of the issue and help you narrow down the root cause.&#xA;Use a Debugger Most modern programming languages come with a debugger that allows you to step through your code and inspect variables at runtime. This is an invaluable tool for debugging complex issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Programming Languages in 2023</title>
      <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/top-5-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 12:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sheel2007.github.io/top-5-languages/</guid>
      <description>As technology continues to evolve at an unprecedented pace, programming languages remain essential tools for developers to create and innovate. The right programming language can help you build anything from simple scripts to complex web applications, mobile apps, and artificial intelligence systems. With that in mind, let&amp;rsquo;s explore the top five programming languages to watch in 2023.&#xA;5. Swift Swift is a powerful programming language designed for developing iOS, macOS, watchOS, and tvOS applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Variables and Datatypes</title>
      <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/variables-and-datatypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sheel2007.github.io/variables-and-datatypes/</guid>
      <description>Python is a high level, dynamically typed programming language, which means that a programmer does not need to specify the data type of a variable when creating it. Instead, Python assigns the data type to the variable based on the value it is assigned.&#xA;A variable in Python is a named container that stores a value. Variables can store values of different data types, such as integers, floating-point numbers, strings, and lists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is programming worth learning in 2023?</title>
      <link>https://sheel2007.github.io/is-programming-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 12:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sheel2007.github.io/is-programming-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>So what even is programming? Computer Programming is specific field of engineering. Programming has a wide variety of from automatically buying concert tickets to predicting future stockprices. Progeamming is a skill used by many in things we use everyday.&#xA;What buissness use programmers? Big corporations use programmers for a variety of tasks, such as developing and mantaining software systems, creating and managing databases, analyzing and interpreting data, and automating buisness processes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
